本视频由KiwiCo赞助
This video is supported by KiwiCo.
在2018年年末 太空叉逐渐开始在一个名叫博卡奇卡的宁静小镇周边进行活动
At the end of 2018, SpaceX started to increase their activity in the quiet town of Boca Chica.
后来大家慢慢意识到他们要在这里制造巨大的Starship火箭
It became clear that this was where they were going to start building and testing their massive Starship rockets.
在过去几年 太空叉新雇佣了上百名工人以维持一条24小时运转的生产线
Over the last couple of years, SpaceX have hired hundreds of new workers
to create a constant 24 hour production line.
但太空叉最新招募来的一名员工则可能让每个人大吃一惊
But one of SpaceX's newest recruits caught everyone by surprise.
在发射场周围 人们发现了一个狗窝
Around the launch site, people started to notice a large doghouse
上面写着狗的名字叫“宙斯”
with the name Zeus written above it.
在他们对自己的Starship原型机进行一次压力测试后
After performing a pressure test on one of their Starship prototypes,
发射场周围因为液氮而云雾缭绕 朦胧中出现了一个黄色的身影
the launch area was covered in a cloud of liquid nitrogen and a yellow figure appeared from the mist.
这个小家伙就是“Spot” 由波士顿动力公司制造的机器狗
This little guy is ‘Spot', the robotic dog made by Boston Dynamics.
本期视频我们将了解太空叉为啥买了一条机器狗
In this video, we're going to look at why SpaceX bought a robotic dog.
我们还将了解他们在用这条狗做什么
We're also going to look at what they are doing with the dog
以及类似的机器人将如何在人类首次火星任务中发挥关键作用
and how similar robots could be crucial for the first crewed missions to Mars.
在过去几年太空叉对Starship的几个原型机进行过多次测试
Over the last couple of years SpaceX have been rapidly testing their Starship prototypes.
其中包括对其巨大的燃料罐加注高压气体（或液氮）
This involves filling up the massive fuel tanks with high pressure gas(or liquid nitrogen)
以测试燃料罐能否安全承受他们既定的压力目标
in order to test that the tanks can safely hold their target pressure.
太空叉在测试中直接把燃料罐加压到炸的事情屡见不鲜
During these tests, it's common for SpaceX to push the pressure of the vehicle until it breaks.
如果火箭里面装满了液氧甲烷 那爆炸将是灾难性的
If the vehicle is fully fueled with methane and liquid oxygen, the results can be catastrophic.
因此 发射全程需要对周边进行清场
Because of this, the entire launch site needs to be cleared
博卡奇卡小镇的道路也会封闭
and the public road that runs through Boca Chica needs to be closed.
测试开始的时候 包括太空叉员工在内的所有人都得离发射场至少一英里远
Once the test begins, no one is allowed within at least a mile of the launch site, including SpaceX personnel.
花上几个小时来确保测试后的发射场已恢复安全对于太空叉来说太麻烦了
This isn't ideal for SpaceX since it can take several hours to confirm that the launch pad is safe.
在这段时间里
During this period of time,
太空叉会错过很多可能会帮助他们弄清火箭失效原因的数据
SpaceX misses out on a lot of data which could help them understand how the vehicle failed.
为了尽可能多的获得测试的数据 太空叉买来了Spot
In order to maximize the data captured from these tests, SpaceX bought 'Spot'.
这款机器狗极其灵活 可以爬楼梯 应付各种复杂地形
This robotic dog is incredibly agile with the ability to climb stairs
and deal with the roughest of terrains.
其上装有照相机 传感器和强有力的电机
Loaded with cameras, sensors and powerful electric motors,
使其可以进行视觉避障 这对于一般的轮式机器人是很难的
it can use it's vision to get around obstacles that an ordinary wheeled robot would struggle with.
Spot可以通过Wi-Fi远程控制
Spot can be controlled remotely(via Wi-Fi)
也可以让它按照存储好的既定路线前进
or it can follow specific routes that have been programmed into its memory.
Spot的首次测试安排在太空叉将SN7加压到爆炸的测试中
The first proper test of Spot was during the SN7 test where SpaceX pushed a Starship prototype to failure.
这场测试制造了一大坨液氮引发的水雾
This test created an enormous cloud of liquid nitrogen
久久挥之不去 降低了能见度
which remained at the launch site for a while, causing poor visibility.
在液氮的云雾之中
Amidst the cloud of liquid nitrogen,
人们发现宙斯正在视察原型机的残骸及其周边区域
Zeus was seen inspecting the remains of the prototype and the surrounding area.
宙斯很可能装有多个相机和传感器
Zeus was most likely fitted with cameras and various sensors
从而监测附近燃料管路的泄漏
in order to detect gas leaks from the nearby fueling lines.
相机会为SpaceX提供火箭故障的有用信息
The cameras give SpaceX an idea of how the vehicle failed
以及想要清空发射架并修理燃料系统的损坏点所需执行的事项
and what needs to be done in order to clear the launch pad and fix any damage to the fueling systems.
这让太空叉能够在每个原型机之间持续改进Starship的设计
This allows SpaceX to constantly improve the design of their Starship rocket between each prototype.
有宙斯在事故现场
Having Zeus at the scene of the accident
可以让太空叉获取尽可能多的信息 又不会让员工置身危险之中
allows SpaceX to capture as much information as possible without ever putting humans at risk.
如果太空叉可以在地球上使用这样的机器狗
If SpaceX can use robotic dogs like this here on Earth,
那他们也很可能在火星上也有用
they might also be useful when we finally send humans to Mars.
太空叉的首次火星之旅几乎可以肯定是无人飞行
The first SpaceX trip to Mars will almost certainly be done without humans.
计划是送多艘携带足够物资和设备的Starship到火星表面
The plan is to send multiple Starships to the Martian surface with enough supplies and technology
建立基地并开采水和甲烷
to set up a base and start mining water and methane.
太空叉可以派遣一组类似的机器人去做很多建设工作
SpaceX could take a group of similar robotic creatures to handle a lot of the setup work.
虽然绝大多数大宗货物的升降可以由Starship自带的吊车完成
Although most of the heavy lifting could be done by Starship itself with its onboard crane,
但还有很多建设工作需要更精准平稳的操作
many of the setup jobs will need a more precise and delicate touch.
最常见的火星机器人都是带轮子的
The most common design for Martian robots has always been a vehicle with wheels,
但像Spot这样的四足机器人
but a 4 legged robot like Spot
则在崎岖的火星表面进行避障方面很有优势
could provide an advantage in getting over obstacles like large rocks on the Martian surface.
因为机器人是设计在地球运行的 适宜温度只有-20到45摄氏度
Since it's designed for Earth, Spot only has a temperature range from 45 degrees down to -20.
但可能在未来 太空叉会和波士顿动力公司来一波梦幻联动 出一款特别版Spot
But perhaps in the future, SpaceX could collaborate with Boston Dynamics to create a special version of Spot,
专为火星表面设计！
designed for the Martian surface.
控制火星表面的机器人 最大的问题是时间延迟
One huge problem that comes with controlling robots on Mars is the time delay.
因为指令需要大约14分钟才能到达火星
Since it takes around 14 minutes to send data to Mars,
所以控制像好奇号这样的火星车是一个非常漫长的过程
controlling robots like the Curiosity rover is an incredibly slow process.
好奇号每天只能走100米 每个动作都要非常小心地执行
Curiosity can only travel around 100 meters per day and each movement has to be carefully planned.
所以Spot在火星上最合适的使用场景是在人类登陆火星之后
The most useful scenario for Spot on Mars would be to aid humans while they are on the surface.
从火星居住基地实时控制Spot
Spot could be controlled in real time from a Martian habitat,
进行设备搭建 避免人类直面火星恶劣的大气环境
allowing equipment to be set up without subjecting humans to the harsh Martian atmosphere.
当人类登上火星之后 它们可以记录并处理信息的速度会比现在快得多
Once we finally send humans to Mars, they will be able to record and process information at a much higher rate
than the rovers that currently occupy the planet.
太空叉的演示告诉我们 人类是有极限的
But as SpaceX has shown, humans have their limits.
未来我们人类很可能要和我们的机器人朋友一起手挽手探索茫茫太空
And it seems that our journey into the future of spaceflight won't be done alone
but hand in hand with our robotic friends.
为了实现这一目标 我们需要培养下一代的工程师 技师和科学家 那么有没有一款……
In order for this to happen, we need to create the next generation of engineers, technicians and scientists.
KiwiCo creates super cool hands-on projects designed to get kids thinking about concepts in STEAM like science, technology, engineering, art and math.
Each monthly crate is designed by experts and tested by kids, and includes an interesting project to build like this infinity mirror.
It's back to school time, but this year it's a little different.
Kids are having to do most of their learning online.
KiwiCo is a brilliant way to give them some hands-on learning and get them away from the computer.
KiwiCo has 8 different subscription options, with crates for different age groups and topics.
Each project provides kids with hours of entertainment and teaches them something new every month.
Each box also comes with all the supplies needed for that month's project,
so there's no need for extra runs to the store.
To support Primal Space and try out KiwiCo,
visit kiwico.com/primalspace to get your first month for free.
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.